A Guide to the Papers of Milton L. Grigg, 1930-1981
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Milton L. Grigg 1930-1981
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6478-b
This collection consists of 910 items (6 Hollinger boxes, 2 linear feet).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The adittional Grigg Papers were given to the Library on July 10, 1985, by Mrs. Milton Grig of Charlottesville, Virginia.
Scope and Content Information
This addition to the Milton L. Grigg Papers contains 910 items, 1930-1981, chiefly the personal and research papers of Milton L. Grigg (1905-1982), a Charlottesville, Virginia, architect. These papers encompass the entire span of Grigg's career as an architect and reflect his specialization in church architecture, estates, restoration, and historic preservation. The collection includes: correspondence, publications, speeches, architectural drawings, pamphlets, printed material, photographs, newsclippings, book reviews, reports, and research files. A list of Grigg's architectural projects can be found in the control folder.
Organization
The topical organization of the collection has been maintained with minor modification and the folders are arranged alphabetically.
Contents List
- Albemarle County-Exhibitions 1939, 1980, and n. d. (Box 1)
- American Institute of Architects Historic Resource Committee 1979-1980 (Box 1)
- American Institute of Architects Historic Resource Committee 1980 (Box 1)
- Brady, Matthew-Photographs of Virginia (copies) [1911] (Box 1)
- Bremo, Fluvanna County, Va. 1965-1979, and n. d. (Box 1)
- Bremo, Fluvanna County, Va. 1931, 1967, and n. d. (Box 1)
- Calendar-Appointments 1965-1970 (Box 1)
- Calendars 1970-1980 (Box 1)
- Careers in Architecture/Architectural Practice-Lecture at the University of Virginia 1974-1977 (Box 2)
- Christ Church, Charlottesville, Va. 1953 and n. d. (Box 2)
- Christ Church, Middlesex County 1952-1968 (Box 2)
- Christ Church, Middlesex County 1951-1962 (Box 2)
- Church Architecture-General 1950-1960, and n. d. (Box 2)
- Church Architecture-General 1950-1963 (Box 2)
- Church Architecture-General 1965-1981 (Box 2)
- Church Architecture-General n. d. (Box 2)
- Churches-Miscellaneous 1965-1973, and n. d. (Box 3)
- Churches of Virginia-Research 1975 and n. d. (Box 3)
- Correspondence 1938-1976 (Box 3)
- Correspondence 1978-1981 (Box 3)
- Correspondence of M. L. Grigg and I. T. Frary 1935-1936, and 1959 (Box 3)
- Correspondence of M. I. Grigg and Charles E. Peterson 1950 Jul (Box 3)
- Edgemont, Albemarle County 1935, 1984, and n. d. (Box 3)
- The Falls Church-Pulpit Location, Falls Church, Va. 1957 (Box 3)
- Farley Church, Wiltshire, England 1961 (Box 3)
- Farmington, Louisville, Kentucky (ca. 1810) 1946-1976, and n. d. (Box 3)
- Gadsby's Tavern Restoration, Alexandria, Va. 1930-1933, 1949, 1974, and n. d. (Box 4)
- Grigg Biographical Information and Genealogy 1942, 1980, and n. d. (Box 4)
- Grigg Book Reviews 1958-1974 (Box 4)
- Grigg Publications 1939-1981 (Box 4)
- Grigg Publications n. d. (Box 4)
- Grigg Publications, Correspondence re 1940-1959 (Box 4)
- Grigg Speeches 1947-1974 (Box 4)
- Grigg Speeches 1975-1976, and n. d. (Box 5)
- Guild For Religious Architecture 1964-1966 (Box 5)
- Homes-Miscellaneous 1940-1980, and n. d. (Box 5)
- Letters of Fiske Kimball 1935-1954 (Box 5)
- Letters and Article of David L. Holmes 1978-1981 (Box 5)
- Memberships, Committees and Boards 1950-1981, and n. d. (Box 5)
- Miscellaneous Buildings n. d. (Box 5)
- Monticello Restoration 1954-1978, and n. d. (Box 5)
- Mountain View, Albemarle County, Va. (near Alberene) 1933 (Box 6)
- Newsclippings 1953-1974 (Box 6)
- Preservation Lecture at the University of Virginia 1978 Sep (Box 6)
- Ramsey House, Alexandria, Va. 1948-1956, and n. d. (Box 6)
- Ramsey House Restoration Research 1980 and n. d. (Box 6)
- Thomas Jefferson Inn, Charlottesville, Va. 1951 and n. d. (Box 6)
- Travel Brochures 1959-1978 (Box 6)
- Travel Brochures n. d. (Box 6)
- University of Virginia Workshop on Vocational Orientation 1978 Oct (Box 6)
- Vauter's Episcopal Church, Loretto, Va. (2074-69) 1968-1969 (Box 6)
- Airplane View of Monticello 1931 Dec 13 (Box 6)
- Copy of Cartoon re Church Restoration n. d. (Box 6)